SHRIKANT SHARMA

BACKEND DEVELOPER

Mobile: +917000568618

Email: sshrikant919@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Shrikant is a **Backend Developer** who is motivated to apply his passion for programming with his experience in building large-scale applications on both the client side and server sides. He is an experienced Backend engineer who would be excited to craft a good product using **Python/Django**. He has experience in all stages of software's lifecycle, including analysis, developing and testing.

GitHub: https://github.com/shri123sharma

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shrikant-sharma-6293581a1

EDUCATION

B.E. Mechanical Engineering

Aug, 2015 – May, 2019

⇒ Sagar Institute of Research Technology &Science Bhopal

Class XII May, 2015

⇒ Passed from ST Mary's Convent H.S. School, MP Board with 64.60 percent marks.

Class X May, 2013

Passed from ST Mary's Convent H.S. School, MP Board with 72.17 percent marks

EXPERIENCE

1.5 year at BridgeFix Technology Indore

Jun, 2022 – Current

→ Nitrix Project :

- Worked as a Backend Developer for Nitrix, a social media platform focused on user-generated content.
- Developed and implemented additional features for the comment section, including real-time send comment and reply comment.
- Designed and developed a comment section, including creating a post API using django rest framework.
- Design and development of requirements.
- Boost API performance by prefetch_related and select_related.
- Perform unit testing.

⇒ Bridge Fix Company Project:

Website:- https://bridgefix.co/

- Developed and implemented APIs for Bridge Fix Site Company's project, enabling seamless communication between different systems.
- Added an interview section to Bridge Fix Site Company's website, allowing users to schedule and conduct interviews online.

- Utilized Beautiful Soup, a Python library, for web scraping tasks, extracting data from various websites.
- Combined Beautiful Soup and Selenium for comprehensive data extraction, manipulation, and automation.
- Implemented scraping strategies to handle complex HTML structures, error handling, and data cleaning.

□ Inclusive Labor Management Project at Issara:

Website:- https://www.issarainstitute.org/

Issara Institute is an independent NGO. The Issara Institute's mission to combat human trafficking and forced labor through worker empowerment, collaboration with multiple workers and suppliers. Addressed worker issues, resolved problems with suppliers and strategic partners, and provided comprehensive support and guidance to Issara staff in adding and assisting workers."

- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs with Django ModelViewSets, facilitating seamless data access for various stakeholders.
- Enhanced data validation and processing using DRF serializers, resulting in improved data accuracy and reduced errors.
- Performed unit testing and integration testing to identify and address bugs and issues in the API code.

3 Months internship In Python at Livewire for live careers Indore, (M.P.)

Jan 2022-April 2022

□ I Started Python Developer Career from Livewire for live careers worked on Banking project with Python, Pharmacy management system with used (Python, Django, HTML, CSS)

KEY SKILLS

- ➡ Python, Django, DRF, Celery.
- Devop's (Docker, GitHub).
- ⇒ Familiarity with HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- ⇒ Beautifulsoup, PostgreSQL.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

- Backend software developer having experience in developing RESTful API's using Django, DRF, Celery Familiar
- with building Versioned API's supporting multiple frontend apps across web and mobile

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Date of Birth: 8 November, 1997

Languages Known: English, Hindi (Proficient in speaking, reading, and writing)